fashionplaytes.com 2013-03-30

# Privacy Policy

Effective Date: 11/1/12 

This Privacy Policy outlines FashionPlaytes, Inc.’s policy regarding our online collection of personal information and how we use and share that information. FashionPlaytes is committed to creating a safe website and protecting the privacy of our users. Please read our Privacy Policy below in order to fully understand our approach to user safety and the collection and use of personal information.

We strive to ensure that the FashionPlaytes, Inc.’s website, Privacy Policy and information collection procedures comply with the guidelines and rules published in the United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We encourage you to visit  <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html> to find out more about the policy and children’s privacy protection. 

Anyone can design and explore on FashionPlaytes.com. It is free and registration is not required. Some areas of the site, however, are reserved for registered users who have obtained their parents’ permission to use the site. 

## Privacy Summary

We neither sell nor share your information with outside companies or third parties. When you purchase from our online store, we collect your name, billing and shipping addresses, phone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. You provide this information so we can process and ship your order. We respect your privacy by not selling or sharing this information. 

We do encourage designers & parents to sign-up for our mailing list. These emails provide you with advanced notice of sales, new merchandise, and other events. But, of course, you have the freedom to add or remove your name from our list at any time. 

## Who needs to register?

Registering is only required for those designers who want to save a garment to their closet or be included in other special activities and promotions. 

## What info is collected?

FashionPlaytes.com does not collect more personal information than is reasonably necessary to permit a child to participate in activities on the site. 

FashionPlaytes, Inc. may collect personal information that is voluntarily provided by you when you order a product, enter a promotion, answer our polls or surveys, register as a member on the site, sign up for additional services on our Websites, or communicate with us by mail, telephone or electronically. 

When a visitor to FashionPlaytes.com wants to post something on the site (such as photos or comments in our gallery), we ask designers to provide info that is not personally identifiable. This information is included with their posted content and not used for any other purposes. All postings to FashionPlaytes.com are screened by adult staff members before appearing on the site to help ensure children’s online safety and privacy. Users are not allowed to post any personally identifiable information. 

When a designer wants to register on FashionPlaytes.com, we ask for the following information: 

  * Designer’s first name, last initial and username/display name
  * Designer’s password, secret question and answer
  * Designer’s email address
  * Designer’s day of birth and age
  * Designer’s city, state, zip code, and country
  * Parent or guardian’s e-mail address

This information is requested regardless of the age of the designer. 

## Use and Disclosure of Information

We use birth dates to validate ages. Birthdates, city, state, zip code and country are collected to help us develop the most appropriate content for our visitors. None of this information is sold or rented to any third parties. E-mail addresses are used to communicate with members and their parents about activities on the site and other features. With consent of a parent, we send requested information to both the children’s and parent’s email addresses as well, including the FashionPlaytes newsletter and information about specific FashionPlaytes events. 

FashionPlaytes may share personal information with third party vendors engaged by us to perform various administrative, technical, and processing functions. These service providers are not permitted to use personal information for other purposes and are required to maintain it in confidence. In addition, we may share personal information with third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to: protect the security and integrity of our website; establish, assert, or defend our legal rights and those of others; respond to judicial process; provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation related to public safety; or, to the extent permitted or required under applicable law. 

We encourage parents to be involved with all of their child’s online activities. 

## Important Information for Parents

Under the Childre’s Online Privacy Protection Act, FashionPlaytes is permitted to collect the email address of a child under 13 in order to respond to a one-time request by them for information, — for example, sending an email about our website being launched. We use this information to respond to the one request only, and delete your child’s email address from our system after doing so. Only users over the age of 13 can subscribe to our newsletters. 

## Which areas on FashionPlaytes.com require Designer registration?

Registering is only required for those designers who want to save a garment to their closet or be included in other special activities and promotions. 

## Tell-A-Friend Messaging

There are several places on FashionPlaytes.com where kids can send an email or SMS message to a friend telling them about the site or a garment they have designed. The Tell-A-Friend form asks for the sender’s first name and their friend’s email address or mobile phone number. The e-mail address or mobile phone number is used only to send a message with information about FashionPlaytes to the friend. It is not stored by FashionPlaytes or used for any other purpose. 

## Links to Other Sites and Additional Site Features

Some pages (e.g. our games and chat areas) may have the look and feel of being on our site, however the information collected on these pages may not be covered under our privacy statement. All information collected on those sites is owned and controlled by that company’s privacy statement. Our privacy statement does apply to the information collected on these co-branded sites. You should read the privacy statement of our co-branded partner. 

Our Site includes links to other Websites (such as our blog) whose privacy practices may differ from those of FashionPlaytes. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Website you visit. 

## Does FashionPlaytes use cookies?

FashionPlaytes uses cookies (small text files placed on your computer’s hard drive) to determine the number of unique visitors to our website over a given period, to improve the website, and, if you have registered, to recognize you when you return to the site. We do not store any personal information in cookies or link information collected through cookies to your personal information. You can always disable cookies on your computer by selecting the appropriate setting in your browser’s preferences or options menu. 

## Tracking Technologies & Third Party Cookies

The use of cookies by our partners is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. 

We use a third-party tracking service, which uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about our visitors to our site in the aggregate to capture usage and volume statistics. Some of our business partners (e.g., Google Analytics) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by FashionPlaytes only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third-party. 

## Log Data

FashionPlaytes’ web servers automatically collect log data about visitors to our site. This data typically includes the URL of the website you are coming from, the Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of the visit, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. FashionPlaytes uses this information to learn about how our website is used, and to improve the site. We may share aggregated log data and/or log data that does not identify you personally with third parties. 

## Web Beacons (Clear Gifs)

Our third party tracking utility company employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information. 

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us at [customercare@fashionplaytes.com](mailto:customercare@fashionplaytes.com)

## How can parents update and delete info?

Designers and parents can view, correct, update and delete personal information provided in the registration process at any time. They will need the registered child’s first name, username, date of birth and password. Parents can prevent further collection or use of their child’s personal information by deleting that child’s registration or by unsubscribing the child from the FashionPlaytes [customercare@fashionplaytes.com](mailto:customercare@fashionplaytes.com). 

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under age 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child’s Personal Information. 

## Questions or Concerns?

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding FashionPlaytes’ privacy policy and/or practices, please contact us by calling, writing, or emailing us at: 

FashionPlaytes, Inc. 500 Cummings Center, Suite 4100, Beverly, MA 01915  
1-800-277-2318   
Attn: Privacy Director  
Email: [support@fashionplaytes.com](mailto:support@fashionplaytes.com)   
PRIVO™’s Privacy Assurance Program (“PPAP”)

[](http://www.privo.com/fashionplaytes.htm "Privo Privacy Certified") FashionPlaytes is a participant in PRIVO™’s Privacy Assurance Program (“PPAPs”). As part of  participating in the PPAP, FashionPlaytes adheres to the strict information collection, use and  disclosure requirements. PRIVO is an independent, third party organization committed to safeguarding children’s personal information collected online, and to helping parents and their children exercise control over personal information while exploring the Internet. The certification seal posted on this page indicates that FashionPlaytes has established privacy practices and has agreed to submit to PRIVO’s oversight and consumer dispute resolution process. If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact us at FashionPlaytes toll free 1-800- 277-2318 or privacy@fashionplaytes.com. If you have further concerns after you have contacted FashionPlaytes, you can contact  PRIVO directly at[ privacy@PRIVO.com](mailto:privacy@PRIVO.com).
